Daniju Farouq Backend developer

Summary

Result-driven backend developer with 4 years of experience in developing and maintaining server side logic across several industries including e-commerce, gaming, and healthcare with core knowledge of Javascript, Typescript, Python, Golang, API development, microservices, databases, and system design.

Skills

Javascript | Typescript | Python | Golang | Node.js | Nestjs | Django | Flask | React | MongoDB | SQL | Redis | Graphql | Git | Docker | AWS | RabbitMQ | Tensorflow | Microservices | Agile Methodology | CI/CD | Jenkins

Experience

2024/02 - present Lagos, Nigeria

Javascript developer

YIP online ☑

- reduced company's production time by 25% by setting up CI/CD pipeline.
- Spearheaded the development of several features and products from planning and design phase through development stage to production.
- handled deployment of several services on cloud providers including AWS (ec2, elastic beanstalk, EKS, CodeDeploy) and google cloud platform (GCP).

2023/01 - 2024/01 Lagos, Nigeria

Backend developer

Gamepride Inc 🛮

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to plan, design and integrate new features.
- built a back-end system for matching game players across the globe with up to 90% accuracy using **Nestjs**.
- Reduced **unit tests** time my 15% through code optimisation.

2023/01 - 2023/12

software engineer (virtual internship)

Y-Combinator

- Developed **Node.js server** for a human resource web application which brought about 40% increase in staff's productivity.
- rebuilt the **user interface** of a human resource web app with **React** resulting in a customer satisfaction index of 10 out of 10.

Certificates

Meta Backend developer 🛮

Gained expertise in API, Backend development, Cloud services, and Databases through hands-on labs and assignments.

Projects

Gadget-x ♂

E-commerce project

- Integrated authentication strategies for customer and administrator using JWT and Passport.
- Integrated fast and secure payment processing with paystack.
- Increased response speed leading to enhanced user experience by integrating server side resource **caching with Redis**.

Skills - Node.js, MongoDB, redis, paystack.

backend - github.com/Horlarhyinka/gadget-x-ap ♂ i frontend - github.com/Horlarhyinka/gadget-x ♂ preview - gadget-x.vercel.app/ ♂

Littlelemon 2

Content management system(project)

- developed server-side logic for a restaurant booking platform using **Django**.
- Crafted **UX optimised** server rendered components.

preview - littlelemon-y7q1.onrender.com ☑ Github - github.com/Horlarhyinka/littlelemon0 ☑

Education

2019/11 - 2023/12 **BSc Botany**Lagos, Nigeria *University of Lagos*